Finding Aid for the North American New Music Festival Archive, 1983-1995
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
North American New Music Festival Archive, 1983-1995
Mus. Arc. 13
North American New Music Festival (Buffalo, N.Y.)
13 boxes
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
This archive contains documents related to the planning and production the North American New Music Festival, a series of annual festivals of contemporary art music sponsored by the University at Buffalo Department of Music from 1983 to 1993, in 1995, and in 1996.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
The bulk of the material was received in 1996 from the Music Department; additional photographs of the festival were purchased in 2007.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Alternate Forms
Photographs in the collection have been digitized and are available in University Libraries Digital Collections.
Historical Note
The North American New Music Festival was founded in 1983 by Yvar Mikhashoff and Jan Williams, faculty members of the University at Buffalo Music Department and dedicated proponents of contemporary and avant-garde art music. Their aim was to produce, over a ten-day period, a concentrated series of concerts and related events at multiple Buffalo-area locations. These annual music festivals featured a wide range of modern musical styles composed and performed both by emerging creative musicians and by established composers of national and international reputation.
The Festivals were held in March or April in the years between 1983 and 1992, in October of 1993, in February of 1995, and in April of 1996, with events occurring in more than a dozen locations, including concert halls, art galleries, churches, theaters, and cabarets. The works of more than 300 composers were presented, including many world premieres.
The Festivals were funded primarily through grants from a variety of sources, including the National Endowment for the Arts and Meet The Composer, Inc.
Festival co-founder Yvar Mikhashoff was a widely-respected world-class pianist and concert producer, charismatic in his ability to attract participation and support. After his untimely death in 1993, a one-year hiatus in the course of the Festivals occurred. The absence of his personal leadership and that of Jan Williams, who retired from the Music Department in 1996, together with an austere funding climate, resulted in the eventual demise of the Festival. The final two Festivals were produced by the University's newly-opened Center for the Arts, under the direction of Robert Chumbley.
Scope and Content Note
This archive consists primarily of materials related to the planning and production of individual North American New Music Festivals from 1983 to 1993. It comprises twelve boxes (nine of paper documents, one of paper documents and computer diskettes, and two of photographs;). It does not contain scores to, or recordings of, music performed at the Festivals (however, see Related Resources for recordings).
Six series make up the archive: Artists and Ensembles, Promotion and Publicity, Funding, Festival Operations, Miscellaneous, and Photographs. The Promotion and Publicity series is organized chronologically by Festival year. Festival Operations is divided into four subseries: Budgets and Financial Projections, Concert Planning and Logistics, Vendors and Venues, and Forms.
The degree of completeness of these papers is highly variable, as is the level of formality. For example, although there are many budget worksheets that appear to be preliminary drafts and working papers, there are few, if any, final reports of a financial nature. Similarly, there are many handwritten lists, annotated outlines, and copies of unsigned contracts, but little that conclusively documents decisions made. On the other hand, the very ad-hoc nature of many items provides a glimpse into the complexities of operating the Festival.
The Promotion and Publicity series, with its printed concert programs (1983-1990, 1992-1993) and numerous newspaper reviews of individual concerts, is a particularly rich source of information on the content of the Festivals and their reception by music critics.
Arrangement
Arranged into six series:
I. Correspondence with artists and ensembles
II. Promotion and publicity
III. Funding agencies
IV. Festival operations
V. Miscellaneous
VI. Photographs
Container List
- Correspondence with Artists and Ensembles, 1983-1993, I.; Folders 1-238
  Correspondence, promotional materials, curricula vitae, agreements, and similar items relating to composers, performers, performing groups, and other creative artists who participated in, were considered for participation in, or inquired about participation in the North American New Music Festival.
  Arranged alphabetically by name.
  - 5th Species 1991-1992, some undated, 27 leaves (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Amherst Saxophone Quartet 1984, 4 leaves (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - AMM Group of London (Musical group) 1985, 1 leaf (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Andolina, Salvatore 1987, 1 leaf (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Arcuri, Serge, undated, 1 information packet (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Arditti, Irvine 1987-1988, 18 leaves (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Array Music 1990-1992, some undated, 31 items (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ashley, Robert 1988-1989, 21 leaves (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Austin, Larry 1982-1984, 3 leaves (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Ayers, Lydia, undated, 1 leaf (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Babbitt, Milton 1984, 2 leaves (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bach, Michael 1988, 6 items (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bacon, John, Jr 1992, 2 leaves (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Barrett, Richard 1989, 1 leaf (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Bartlett, Martin 1987-1988, 5 leaves (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Basinski, Michael, undated, 8 leaves (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bennett, Mark 1987-1990, 5 leaves (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Bentley, Karen 1987, 4 items (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bergamo, John 1984, 1 leaf (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Bidlack, Rick 1991, 6 leaves (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Bigham, James 1987, 2 items (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bird, John 1984, 2 items (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Biscardi, Chester, undated, 1 leaf (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Black, Robert 1984-1988, some undated, 16 items (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Blum, Eberhard 1985, 1 leaf (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Boone, Charles, undated, 1 pamphlet (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Bove, Craig 1989, 8 leaves (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Bowery Ensemble, undated, 1 leaf (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Bresnick, Martin 1992, 3 leaves (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Brown, Earle 1990-1992, 2 leaves (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Brün, Herbert 1986, 1 leaf (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Buckner, Tom, undated, 1 leaf (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra 1985 and 1992, 8 leaves (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Bussotti, Sylvano 1987, 1 leaf (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Buxton, William 1982, 1 leaf (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Cage, John 1987-1992, some undated, 20 leaves (Box 1, Folder 36)
    Includes material related to production of Europera 5
  - California E.A.R. Unit (Musical group) 1984-1985, 8 items (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Carlyss, Earl 1988, 5 items (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Carter, Elliott 1987-1988, 9 leaves (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Casavant, Charles 1984, 5 leaves (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Celli, Joseph 1980-1984, 11 leaves (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Chadabe, Joel 1987-1992, some undated, 17 leaves (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Chamber Concerts Canada 1989, 9 leaves (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Chatham, Rhys, undated, 1 leaf (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Cherney, Lawrence 1987-1990, 12 items (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - CH+K 1991, 1 leaf (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Clapperton, James 1988, 5 leaves (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Cohen, Douglas 1988-1989, 6 leaves (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Colquhoun, Michael, undated, 1 leaf (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Coleman, Ornette 1985, 1 leaf (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Concertino String Quartet 1984, 2 leaves (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Crumb, George 1988-1989, 9 leaves (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Cummings, Conrad 1984, 2 leaves (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Curran, Alvin 1983-1984, some undated, 12 items (Box 1, Folder 54)
    Includes choral scores A way a lone and Riverrun
  - Da Capo Chamber Players, undated, 1 item (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Danish Trio 1983, 2 leaves (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Daugherty, Michael 1986, some undated, 11 leaves (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Dashow, James 1986, 1 leaf (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Davis, Anthony 1983-1989, some undated, 46 leaves (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Degazio, Bruno 1990, 1 leaf (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - De Klerk, Dirk 1993, 2 leaves (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - De Mare, Anthony 1986-1989, 5 leaves (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Derome, Jean, 1 leaf (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Di Pietro, Rocco 1984, 2 leaves (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Dick, Robert 1987-1988, 8 leaves (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Dodge, Charles 1983, 7 leaves (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Dorian Wind Quintet 1985, 1 leaf (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Duo Contemporain 1985, 1 leaf (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Einar Jóhannesson 1988, 2 leaves (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Emery, James 1981-1992, 24 leaves (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Felder, David 1992, some undated, 4 leaves (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Feldman, Morton, undated, 1 leaf (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Fernandez, Robert 1987, 2 leaves (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Foccroulle, Bernard 1983, 7 leaves (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Foss, Lukas 1985-1986, some undated, 4 leaves (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - François, Jean Charles 1983-1988, 6 leaves (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Fulkerson, James 1985, 1 leaf (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Fusco, James 1983, 2 leaves (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Gageego (Musical group) 1983, some undated, 6 leaves (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Galás, Diamánda 1981-1985, some undated, 37 leaves (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Gamelan Son of Lion 1987, 7 leaves (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Ganz, Isabelle 1987-1992, 9 leaves (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - García, Orlando Jacinto 1987-1990, 8 leaves (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Gibson, John 1987, 8 leaves (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Gillock, John 1987-1992, some undated, 15 items (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Glass, Philip, undated, 8 leaves (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Golani-Erdesz, Rivka 1983-1984, 13 leaves (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Goldstein, Malcolm 1983-1985, 38 leaves (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Gordon, Michael, undated, 1 leaf (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Górecki, Henryk 1990, 1 pamphlet (28 p.) (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Greater Buffalo Opera Company 1991-1992, 37 leaves (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Harpans Kraft (Musical group) 1984, 5 leaves (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Harris, Michael 1984, 3 leaves (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Harrison, Lou 1987-1988, 4 leaves (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Hassell, Jon 1987, 7 leaves (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Hausmann, Robert 1985, 1 leaf (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Horwood, Michael S 1984, 1 leaf (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Hyla, Lee 1989, 7 leaves (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Jaffe, David A 1992, 2 leaves (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Jacob, Jeffrey 1982-1983, 6 leaves (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Jarrett, Keith 1983, 2 leaves (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - Jarvinen, Arthur 1992, 2 leaves (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - Johnson, Tom 1985, 7 leaves (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - Johnston, Ben 1983, 1 leaf (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - Kabat, Julie, undated, 1 leaf (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - Kagel, Mauricio 1987-1988, 5 leaves (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Kernis, Aaron Jay 1989, 4 leaves (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - Kikauka, Laura 1989-1990, 4 leaves (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Knussen, Oliver 1987, 1 leaf (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Komorous, Rudolf 1992, 2 leaves (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - Koplewitz, Laura 1983, 1 leaf (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - Kostelanetz, Richard 1983-1984, 6 leaves (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - Kosugi, Takehisa 1992, 2 leaves (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - Kramer, Gregory 1984-1987, 4 items (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - Kronos Quartet 1982-1984, 9 leaves (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - Kryszak, Alan 1988-1989, 9 leaves (Box 3, Folder 116)
  - La Barbara, Joan 1976-1990, 15 leaves (Box 3, Folder 117)
  - La Berge, Ann 1987-1988, 4 leaves (Box 3, Folder 118)
  - Landy, Leigh 1985-1986, 6 leaves (Box 3, Folder 119)
  - Laske, Otto E 1987, 1 leaf (Box 3, Folder 120)
  - Levick, Hugh 1985-1986, some undated, 8 leaves (Box 3, Folder 121)
  - Levine, Jesse 1987-1992, 4 leaves (Box 3, Folder 122)
  - Lewin, Martin 1984, 1 leaf (Box 3, Folder 123)
  - Logos-Duo 1983, 1 leaf (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - Lontano 1983, 1 leaf (Box 3, Folder 125)
  - Lustig, Leila 1985, 2 leaves (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - Macbride, David 1984, 2 leaves (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - Mackey, Steven 1988, 3 leaves (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - McLean, Barton 1983, 1 leaf (Box 3, Folder 129)
  - Maelström Percussion Ensemble 1984, 2 leaves (Box 3, Folder 130)
  - Manes, Stephen 1987, 5 leaves(some undated) (Box 3, Folder 131)
  - Manning, Jane 1984-1988, 5 leaves (Box 3, Folder 132)
  - Marcus, Bunita, undated, 1 leaf (Box 3, Folder 133)
  - Mather, Bruce 1990, 2 leaves (Box 3, Folder 134)
  - McCandless, Michael 1990, 1 leaf (Box 3, Folder 135)
  - McDermott, Vincent 1985, 3 leaves (Box 3, Folder 136)
  - Mead, Philip 1990, 2 leaves (Box 3, Folder 137)
  - Mellnäs, Arne 1985, 1 leaf (Box 3, Folder 138)
  - Mendes, Gilberto 1976, 1 pamphlet (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Metz, Donald 1988-1992, 6 leaves (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - Mikhashoff, Yvar 1983-1992, 4 leaves (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Miranda, Anthony 1987, 1 leaf (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - Montague, Stephen 1983-1990, 27 leaves (Box 3, Folder 143)
  - Montgomery, Roger 1991, 2 leaves (Box 3, Folder 144)
  - Moog, Robert 1991, 1 leaf (Box 3, Folder 145)
  - Moravec, Paul 1986, 3 leaves (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - Moore, Carman, undated, 1 leaf (Box 3, Folder 147)
  - Moss, David 1984, 4 leaves (Box 3, Folder 148)
  - Mott, David 1992, 2 leaves (Box 3, Folder 149)
  - Myska, David 1991, 1 leaf (Box 3, Folder 150)
  - Neill, Ben 1987, 5 leaves (Box 3, Folder 151)
  - Neuburger, Annie 1984, 3 leaves (Box 3, Folder 152)
  - New Music Consort 1988, 1 leaf (Box 3, Folder 153)
  - New Winds (Musical group) 1987-1989, 24 leaves (Box 3, Folder 154)
  - Noyes, Charles, undated, 5 leaves (Box 3, Folder 155)
  - Ohrenstein, Dora 1989, 11 leaves (Box 3, Folder 156)
  - Oliveros, Pauline 1983, 9 leaves (Box 3, Folder 157)
  - Oppens, Ursula 1985, 1 leaf (Box 3, Folder 158)
  - Ørsted, Ole 1984, 1 leaf (Box 3, Folder 159)
  - Ortiz, William 1987, some undated, 9 leaves (Box 3, Folder 160)
  - Papoulis, James 1989, 9 leaves (Box 3, Folder 161)
  - Patton, Chris 1991, 1 leaf (Box 3, Folder 162)
  - Pekarski Percussion Ensemble, undated, 1 leaf (Box 3, Folder 163)
  - Penn, William A 1983, 11 leaves (Box 3, Folder 164)
  - Percussion Group 1985, 4 leaves (Box 3, Folder 165)
  - Peterson, Kyle 1985, 1 leaf (Box 3, Folder 166)
  - Phonemic and Vocal Improvisation Group 1983-1984, 26 leaves (Box 3, Folder 167)
  - Pilgrim, Neva 1985, 2 leaves (Box 3, Folder 168)
  - Pituch, David 1985, 6 leaves (Box 3, Folder 169)
  - Pittsburgh New Music Ensemble 1983-1984, 10 leaves (Box 3, Folder 170)
  - Prezament, Wendy, undated, 1 leaf (Box 3, Folder 171)
  - Pugliese, Michael 1984-1992, 9 leaves (Box 3, Folder 172)
  - Rands, Bernard 1984, 3 leaves and 2 pamphlets (Box 3, Folder 173)
  - Rea, John 1984, 2 leaves (Box 3, Folder 174)
  - Riley, Terry 1992, 2 leaves (Box 3, Folder 175)
  - Ritt, Morey 1992, 1 leaf (Box 3, Folder 176)
  - Rolnick, Neil B 1993, 10 leaves (Box 3, Folder 177)
  - Ross, Eric 1983-1984, 21 leaves (Box 3, Folder 178)
  - Ruders, Poul 1987-1991, 13 leaves (Box 3, Folder 179)
  - Russell, Bill 1985, 4 leaves (Box 3, Folder 180)
  - Rzewski, Frederic 1985-1986, 4 leaves (Box 3, Folder 181)
  - Sahl, Michael, undated, 2 leaves (Box 4, Folder 182)
  - Scheidt, Daniel J 1992, 10 leaves (some undated) (Box 4, Folder 183)
  - Schmidt, Paul 1987-1990, 15 leaves and 1 booklet (Box 4, Folder 184)
  - Schulz, Constance 1985, 14 leaves (Box 4, Folder 185)
  - Schvartz, Haydée, undated, 3 leaves (Box 4, Folder 186)
  - Schwartz, Elliot 1990, 1 leaf (Box 4, Folder 187)
  - Schwartz, Francis 1987, 9 leaves (Box 4, Folder 188)
  - Sellars, James 1984-1985, 6 leaves (Box 4, Folder 189)
  - Shepherd, Stuart, undated, 1 leaf (Box 4, Folder 190)
  - Sims, David 1987, 1 leaf (Box 4, Folder 191)
  - Smalley, Roger, undated, 1 leaf (Box 4, Folder 192)
  - Smith, Stuart 1984, 2 leaves (Box 4, Folder 193)
  - Stiller, Andrew, undated, 1 leaf (Box 4, Folder 194)
  - Simons, Netty 1984, 3 leaves (Box 4, Folder 195)
  - Sound Pressure (Musical group) 1990, 5 leaves (Box 4, Folder 196)
  - Sparnaay, Harry 1985, 1 leaf (Box 4, Folder 197)
  - Speach, Bernadette 1984-1987, 5 items (Box 4, Folder 198)
  - Spectrum Ensemble Berlin 1986, 1 leaf (Box 4, Folder 199)
  - Steiger, Rand 1986, 2 leaves (Box 4, Folder 200)
  - Stevens, Claudia 1982-1984, 7 leaves (Box 4, Folder 201)
  - Stock, David 1986, 2 leaves (Box 4, Folder 202)
  - Stone, Dorothy 1985-1986, 2 leaves (Box 4, Folder 203)
  - String Trio of New York 1987, 2 items (Box 4, Folder 204)
  - Sun Ra Arkestra 1984-1990, 28 leaves (Box 4, Folder 205)
  - Swartz, Steven Nicholas 1987, 10 items (Box 4, Folder 206)
  - Takahashi, Aki 1988, 5 leaves (Box 4, Folder 207)
  - Talking Drums (Musical group) 1992, 2 leaves (Box 4, Folder 208)
  - Teitelbaum, Richard 1987-1988, 8 leaves (Box 4, Folder 209)
  - Tenney, James, undated, 1 leaf (Box 4, Folder 210)
  - Terra Australis 1987-1989, 15 leaves (Box 4, Folder 211)
  - Thibault, Alain 1984-1986, some undated, 10 leaves and 1 booklet (Box 4, Folder 212)
  - Thomson, Virgil 1985-1986, 4 leaves (Box 4, Folder 213)
  - Thow, John 1986, 1 leaf (Box 4, Folder 214)
  - Torke, Michael 1988, 2 leaves (Box 4, Folder 215)
  - Trayle, Mark 1988, some undated, 8 leaves (Box 4, Folder 216)
  - Truax, Barry 1983-1990, some undated, 16 leaves (Box 4, Folder 217)
  - Tudor, David 1992, 2 leaves (Box 4, Folder 218)
  - University of Buffalo Percussion Ensemble 1992, 3 leaves (Box 4, Folder 219)
  - Uitti, Frances-Marie 1987, 4 leaves (Box 4, Folder 220)
  - Vaes, Luk 1991-1992, 5 items (Box 4, Folder 221)
  - Vaillancourt, Pauline, undated, 1 item (Box 4, Folder 222)
  - Valverde, Gabriel, undated, 1 leaf (Box 4, Folder 223)
  - Van de Vate, Nancy, undated, 1 leaf (Box 4, Folder 224)
  - Vérin, Nicolas 1992, 4 leaves (Box 4, Folder 225)
  - Vigeland, Nils 1984-1990, 7 leaves (Box 4, Folder 226)
  - Volans, Kevin 1992, 5 items (Box 4, Folder 227)
  - Vortex 1983-1984, 2 items (Box 4, Folder 228)
  - Ware, Peter, undated, 6 leaves (Box 4, Folder 229)
  - Widoff, Antony 1991, 1 leaf (Box 4, Folder 230)
  - Willey, James 1992, 5 leaves (Box 4, Folder 231)
  - Williams, Diane 1987, 1 leaf (Box 4, Folder 232)
  - Wolfe, Julia, undated, 1 leaf (Box 4, Folder 233)
  - Wolff, Christian 1991, 14 leaves (Box 4, Folder 234)
  - Wuorinen, Charles 1991, 3 leaves (Box 4, Folder 235)
  - Young, La Monte 1990, 8 leaves (Box 4, Folder 236)
  - Zappa, Frank 1984, 6 leaves (Box 4, Folder 237)
  - Zwilich, Ellen Taaffe 1985, 1 leaf (Box 4, Folder 238)
- Promotion, publicity, and news clippings 1983-1995, II.; Folders 239-385
  News releases, program booklets, clippings of concert reviews, promotional flyers, advertisements, and similar materials.
  Divided into subseries by years; arranged chronologically.
  - 1983, A.; Folders 239-248
    - North American New Music Festival North American New Music Festival 1983, [program booklet], circa April 4, 1983, 18 p.: ill., ports.; 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 239)
    - Buffalo News New music festival, [display advertisement], circa April 4, 1983, 2 leaves (Box 5, Folder 240)
    - Events and openings, [source unidentified], circa April 4, 1983, 2 leaves (Box 5, Folder 241)
    - Stiller, Andrew Johnston's musical probes reveal some gems, some clinkers, in Buffalo News, circa April 8, 1983, 2 leaves (Box 5, Folder 242)
    - Stiller, Andrew Cage retrospective: marvelous marathon, in Buffalo News, circa April 9, 1983, 2 leaves (Box 5, Folder 243)
    - Trotter, Herman Schafer's creativity defies categorization, in Buffalo News, circa April 11, 1983, 2 leaves (Box 5, Folder 244)
    - Young, Kenneth Experimental vocalist has rich vocabulary of sound, in Buffalo News, April 11, 1983, 2 leaves (Box 5, Folder 245)
    - Young, Kenneth Tremont Quartet, Manes excel in Chadwick pieces, in Buffalo News, April 12, 1983, 2 leaves (Box 5, Folder 246)
    - Trotter, Herman Festival offers lunchtime crowd a perky, welcome performance, in Buffalo News, April 12, 1983, 2 leaves (Box 5, Folder 247)
    - Canadian Broadcasting Corporation [Correspondence], July 21, 1983, 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 248)
  - 1984, B.; Folders 249-262
    - North American New Music Festival North American New Music Festival 1984, [program booklets], circa April 1, 1984, 18 p.: ill., ports.; 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 249)
      2 booklets, one containing inserted program corrections, one with annotations on back cover.
    - State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Dept North American New Music Festival 1984, [news release], circa April 1, 1984, 8 leaves (Box 5, Folder 250)
    - Young, Kenneth Grab bag of fine performances offered at new music festival, in Buffalo News, April 8, 1984, 2 leaves (Box 5, Folder 251)
    - Trotter, Herman Marathon performance shows pianist's artistry, in Buffalo News, circa April 9, 1984, 2 leaves (Box 5, Folder 252)
    - Trotter, Herman New music festival airs three composers, in Buffalo News, April 10, 1984, 2 leaves (Box 5, Folder 253)
    - Young, Kenneth Leisurely musical stroll takes cue from truism, in Buffalo News, circa April 11, 1984, 2 leaves (Box 5, Folder 254)
    - Trotter, Herman Solo gourd played tongue in cheek stars in new-music fest, in Buffalo News, circa April 11, 1984, 2 leaves (Box 5, Folder 255)
    - Putnam, Thomas Cello improvisations paint a portrait of pictures at exhibition, in Buffalo News, April 12, 1984, 4 leaves (Box 5, Folder 256)
    - Parris, Roger 'New from New York' lures attentive audience, in Buffalo News, circa April 12, 1984, 2 leaves (Box 5, Folder 257)
    - Stiller, Andrew A few bugs here and there in computer music at UB, in Buffalo News, circa April 13, 1984, 2 leaves (Box 5, Folder 258)
    - Stiller, Andrew Musical collage links composer, mentor, in Buffalo News, circa April 14, 1984, 2 leaves (Box 5, Folder 259)
    - Trotter, Herman Surprise caps lush finale of UB music festival, in Buffalo News, April 15, 1984, 2 leaves (Box 5, Folder 260)
    - [State University of New York at Buffalo] New music festival: aficionados, neophytes treated to wide-ranging, week-long musical array, in Reporter, April 19, 1984, 2 leaves (Box 5, Folder 261)
    - Trotter, Herman SUNY Buffalo: Ives/Austin 'Life pulse music' premiere, in Musical America, September, 1984, 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 262)
  - 1985, C.; Folders 263-280
    - North American New Music Festival North American New Music Festival 1985, [program booklet], circa April 1, 1985, 22 p.: ill., ports.; 28 cm. (Box 5, Folder 263)
    - [State University of New York at Buffalo] New music festival, in Magnet, circa April 1, 1985, 3 leaves (Box 5, Folder 264)
    - Roger Parris 'Buffalo gala' program gets new-music fest off to good start, in Buffalo News, April 14, 1985, 2 leaves (Box 5, Folder 265)
    - Stiller, Andrew Mikhashoff, at piano, shows it takes more than two to tango, in Buffalo News, April 15, 1984, 2 leaves (Box 5, Folder 266)
    - Opening night at the North American New Music Festival, [captioned photo], in Reporter, circa April 15, 1985, 2 leaves (Box 5, Folder 267)
    - Everman, Welch D New music at festival is inventive, in Buffalo News, circa April 15, 1985, 3 leaves (Box 5, Folder 268)
    - Putnam, Thomas Three strong performances in a cabaret, in Buffalo News, April 16, 1985, 2 leaves (Box 5, Folder 269)
    - Stiller, Andrew New music festival continues to be showcase for virtuosity, in Buffalo News, April 16, 1985, 1 leaf (Box 5, Folder 270)